Andrew (Drew) Harris

287 Alabama St, Spindale, NC / 828.748.9438 / harris.db92@gmail.com / portfolio: dbharris92.github.io

ABOUT

I have gained a wide range of experience in my first two years of municipal planning. I have been the primary planning staff for the Board of Planning & Adjustment and Board of Commissioners. I have researched and prepared reports for legislative and quasi-judicial decisions and presented in both empty rooms and crowded auditoriums effectively. I am a skilled GIS user who uses spatial information to support my planning work. My young family and I are seeking to relocate to the Upstate to enjoy the high quality of life offered there.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Planner II, Town of Forest City, NC

Planning Responsibilities

May 2018 - Current

- Prepared and presented a variety of technical and administrative reports to local governing boards
- Interpreted, explained, and applied zoning and development regulations to the public
- Reviewed site plans and zoning applications for compliance with Town regulations
- Served as Staff Officer to Historic Preservation Commission, guided Local Historic Landmark designation process for the Florence Mill
- Represented the Town on regional planning efforts, including SPOT 6.0 identification and prioritization GIS Responsibilities
 - Maintained and expanded Town's GIS for utility assets, cemetery plats, zoning, and planning efforts
 - Developed an enterprise GIS using postGIS, GeoServer, and QGIS
 - Created web maps and applications displaying GIS data for internal and public use

Teaching Assistant, Intro to GIS and Digital Image Processing Labs

Fall 2017 - Spring 2018

Appalachian State University, Department of Geography and Planning

- Instructed undergraduate labs using ArcGIS to perform spatial analysis, data acquisition, cartography, and data management
- Developed a new lab, based on open-source and public data, and open-source software (QGIS)
- Maintained regular office hours to assist students with labs and project assignments

Teller I

May 2016 - August 2017

- South State Bank, Charleston, South Carolina
 - Served customers efficiently, accurately, and confidentially according to institutional service standards
 - Responsible for receiving and disbursing cash shipments, stocking, and balancing of branch vault
 - Remained in compliance with regulatory standards, advised customers of relevant policies and regulations

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION

UNC School of Government

Expected April 2020

Zoning Official Certification

Appalachian State University, Department of Geography and Planning

Master of Arts in Geography, Geographic Information Science

Summer 2018

Winthrop University, College of Arts and Sciences

Bachelor of Arts in History, GPA 3.50

Spring 2014

RELEVANT SKILLS

Applications: ArcGIS Suite, QGIS, Inkscape (Intermediate), CAD, Adobe Illustrator (Novice)

Programming Languages: Leaflet.is (Intermediate), SQL, Python (Novice)